A Guide to the Papers of the Stuart-Baldwin Families, 1764-1884
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Isonhower, Elizabeth (1824 Oct)
Isonhower, Samuel (1820 Apr 4)
Jackson, Bolton (1834 Nov 26, Dec 11; 1836 Oct 3; 1837 Jun 16)
Jackson, Thomas (1821 Jul 7)
Janney, John (1791 Jan 5)
Janney, Hopkins & Hull (1838 Jun 15)
Jefferson, Thomas (1780 Jul 14, Sep 1 copies of a land grant in legal & financial papers; originals in Thomas Jefferson Papers)
Jeffress, John C. (1836 Aug 9)
Jenkins, William & Sons (1838 Jan 10, Mar 2, Mar 10)
Johnson, Lain J. (1790 Jan 18, Mar 28)
Johnson, C. (1824 Sep 4)
Johnson, Chapman (1833 May 4, Jul 7)
Johnson, Curtis P. (1845 Aug 20, Oct 17)
Johnson, George Nicholson (1841 Aug 16; 1845 Aug 4)
Johnston, Charles (1792 July 21)
Johnston, Edward William (1838 Nov 19)
Johnston, Zachariah (1790 Oct 21, in the letter dated 1790 Dec 2, he discusses controversy in General Assembly re the assumption by Congress of state and Confederation debt; 1795 Mar 6)
Johnstone, Edward (1839 Nov 4; 1840 Apr 9, Dec 14)
Joliffe, John (1830 May 12; 1833 July 18)
Jones, H. (1815 Aug 18)
Jones, Robert S. (1847 May 24)
Jouett, John (1791 Jan 16)
Kelly, Robert (1831 June 7)
Kelso, John S. (1839 Jul 23)
Kennerly, Thomas (1826 Apr 25)
Kennerly, William (1825 Apr 4, Nov 14)
Kenney, John (1833 July 18, Dec 4; 1834 Oct 26; 1836 Feb 8, Oct 1; 1837 Oct 16, Nov 28; 1839 Jul 3, Jul 19; 1841 Sep 1, Sep 30, Oct 6; 1842 Feb 16 re congratulations on Baldwin becoming Judge of the Court of Appeals)
Kenney, Joseph (1830 Oct 24)
Keyes, James (1839 Jan 3)
Keyton, Jane (1834 Feb 17)
Kinkaid, Thomas (1836 Mar 29)
Kinney, Nicholas C. (1833 Dec 16; 1836 Sep 2; 1838 Mar 5; 1842 Sep 26)
Kinney, William (1826 Apr 8)
Kinsolving, G.W. (1832 Nov 7)
Kirby, Eph[ram] (1798 Jul 14)
Kirk, William B. (1822 Jan 23; 1823 Jan 15)
Koontz, John (1837 Feb 20)
Kownslar, F.A. (1831 Jul 18; 1834 Jun 13, Sep 18; 1835 Apr 10, Sep 28)
Kyle, David (1795 Feb 14)
Kyle, Jeremiah (1819 Jun 16)
Kyle, R & H (1821 Feb 27)
Kyle, William S. (1833 Sep 22)
Laidby, James M. (1831 Jun 6, Sep 21; 1837 Jun 10; 1838 Jun1, Jun 3; 1841 Nov 29)
Laird, John (1838 Jan 2)
Lambert, William (1831 Oct 20; 1835 Nov 23; 1836 Feb 20, Jun 7, Jun 28)
Lanahan, William (1836 Dec 29; 1837 Jan 14, Sept 17)
Lane, Arthur F. (1831 May 26)
Lang, Mary (1820 Nov 15)
Langhorn, William (1838 May 27)
Langster, Robert (1833 Aug 22)
Lauck, Isaac (1841 Jan 12)
Lawrason, R.S. (1821 Dec 10)
Lawson, Gavin (1802 Jul 24)
Leach, Collin (1838 Jan 3; 1839 Dec 21)
Leach, James (1836 Nov 11)
Leake, Samuel (1834 Nov 30)
Lecky, Thomas (1833 May 8, Jun 18; 1834 Oct 10)
Ledbetter, Coleman (1822 Mar 30)
Lee, George H. (1831 Sep 8; 1835 Jul 4; 1836 Jul 23; 1837 Dec 19)
Leeke, Samuel (1834 Jan 1)
Leigh, William (1824 Oct 25)
Leon, P. (1836 Aug 29)
Lester, Samuel (1828 Aug 21)
Leuba, Peter H. (1823 Apr 10, May 2; 1825 Jun 1)
Lewis, A. (1792 Feb 27)
Lewis, Charles H. (1838 Jul 4)
Lewis, Fielding (1772 Oct 17)
[Lewis, G.W.] (1818 Jun 26)
Lewis, Mary Jane (1823 Apr 24, May 8)
Lewis, S.S. (1834 Oct 24)
Lewis, Samuel H. (1834 Oct 30; 1846 Mar 4)
Lewis, Thomas (1787 July 9)
Leyburn, A, Dr. (1843 Nov 15; 1844 Dec 4)
Lidball, J. (1853 Jan 26)
Lincoln, Abraham, of Harrisonburg (1840 Mar 12)
Lind, George (1818 Jan 30)
Linn, Samuel (1832 Jan 12)
Littington, A. (1834 Dec 25 re recovering a slave that was stolen)
Locker, Archibald (1828 Feb 6)
Lockett, John P. (1835 Apr 18)
Lockhart, Patrick (1790 Dec 21; 1791 Feb 17; 1804 Feb 11)
Lockland, Joel (1821 Jan 2)
Logan, Samuel (1847 May 26)
Lucke, Gustavus (1812 Feb 20, Jul 14, Aug 18, Oct 6; 1814 Mar 11, Apr 6, May 18, Jun 25; 1816 Nov 1)
Lupton, J. (1839 Jan 14)
Lyons, James (1840 Sep 1 re a Whig Convention)
McBride, J.H. (1836 Oct 20)
McCarrell, J.L. (1798 Nov 24)
McChesney, Robert (1834 Jan 21)
McChesney, Samuel (1795 Jun 10)
McClanahan, Elijah (1832 Aug 14)
McClure, William H. (1836 Oct 28)
McCormick, Cyrus Hall (1840 Jun 1; 1841 Mar 24, Apr 26)
McCoullough, Thomas (1841 May 24)
McCridie & Macmillan (1795 Mar 18)
McCue, James A. (1836 Nov 23)
McCue, John (1835 Apr 27)
McDaniel & McConkle (1843 Dec 4)
McDowell, H.H. (1834 Dec 11, Dec 24)
McDowell, James (1833 Dec 30; 1835 Nov 17; 1836 Oct 22, Nov 1)
McDowell, John (1820 May 13; 1835 Dec 26; 1838 Mar 26)
McElhenney, M. (1840 Mar 18 re his political debate)
Macfarland, William H. (1848 Jun 3)
McGinnis, E. (1826 Jun 18)
McHenry, James (1821 Mar 27)
McKey, David (1846 Jul 25)
McMahon, William (1833 Mar 23, May 30, Jun 22; 1835 Aug 12; 1837 May 23)
McNutt, R. (1829 Mar 11)
McPherson, Major John, (1834 Apr 2 re training and regimental muster)
Madison, Eliza (1790 Feb 22)
Magill, Charles (1826 Feb 22)
Magill, James (1790 Apr 26)
Magill, John S. (1832 Jul 7)
Mains, Thomas (1832 May 8)
Makky, John (1790 Aug 31)
Malcom, Robert (1833 Apr 20)
Mann, Isaac (1821 Mar 11)
Manson, R.E. (1844 Jan 31)
Marmion, N. (1833 Mar 28, Apr 16, Aug 27; 1834 May 5, Jul 21)
Martin, A. (1835 Jun 9; 1836 Dec 30; 1837 Mar 18, May 29; 1840 Sep 14, Nov 15)
Martin, Mrs. F. (1840 Jun 6, Jul 8)
Martin, Thomas (1831 Aug 6; 1832 May 16, Jun 15; 1834 Mar 18; 1836 Apr 6)
Mason, James M. (1836 Nov 12; 1844 May 29)
Mason, John T. (1791 Sep 7; 1792 Aug 10)
Mason, Joseph M. (1836 Jul 9)
Mathews, Catherine (1785 May 20)
Mathews, Daniel (1834 Mar 10)
Mathews, Richard (1782 Mar 24, Apr 21; 1791 Feb 6)
Mathews, Samp[son] (1785 May 20; 1790 May 22, 30 re elopement of his daughter, Jun 8, Oct 24)
May, E. (1826 Feb 11, Jul 28, Aug 28)
Matthews, Daniel (1833 Sep 9)
Mayburry, Thomas (1825 Jan 31; 1828 Mar 3; 1830 Apr 9; 1831 May 13; 1832 Nov 1; 1833 Apr 19, May 9, Jun 14; 1835 Nov 10; 1836 Jul 23)
Mayo, Frederick A. (1837 Nov 7; 1846 Sep 11)
Maze, C. (1836 Dec 3)
Maze, John Joseph (1831 Aug 2; 1833 Aug 15, 28; 1834 Jan 7, Apr 10; 1835 Feb 19, Apr 27, May 4, May 28, Dec 14; 1836 Feb 25, 27)
[Maze], Joseph (n.d.)
Merry, James (1819 Aug 8)
Michie, Thomas Johnson (1846 Jun 6)
Miller, Henry (1836 Apr 1)
Miller, J.R. (1843 Sep 12, Dec 2)
Miller, John (1814 Sep 17, Oct 9, Oct 23; 1815 Mar 6, 13, May 16; 1816 Jan 30, Feb 5, Mar 26)
Miller, S.A. (1842 Aug 18)
Miller, Samuel (1797 Jun 26)
Mitchell, George W. (1831 Jul 7)
Mitchell, H. (1838 Nov 1 re establishing a female academy and procuring a teacher)
Moffett, John (1838 Mar 13, 1839 Jun 3)
Moffett, Thomas S. (1835 Apr 14)
Mohler, Jacob (1835 May 5; 1838 Mar 19, 26)
Montgomery, Joseph F. (1833 Sep 30; 1835 Nov 15; 1836 Jan 1, Oct 11)
Moon, Richard W. (1834 Jul 5)
Moor, D.E. (1839 Mar 20)
Moor, William (1790 May 14)
Moore, A[ndrew] (1791 Jan 7; 1797 Mar 27)
Moore, David (1831 Sep 7, Oct 4; 1832 Apr 7)
Moore, David E. (1831 Feb 5; 1836 Aug 27; 1838 Jan 31)
Moore, N.G. (1837 Dec 2)
Moore, Samuel (1790 Oct 30)
Moore, Samuel McDowell (1840 Feb 14; 1841 Nov 11; 1842 Mar 11, 26)
Morris, Benjamin (1806 Aug 8)
Morris, John (1825 Aug 17; 1826 Apr 14; 1832 Sep 15; 1835 May 18, 25)
Mowry, George (1826 May 27, Nov 10)
Murdaugh, George (1841 Apr 17)
Murdock, Yuelle, Wardrop & Co. (1821 Jul 23; 1825 Oct 22)
Murray, John & Co. (1790 Apr 3, Nov 20)
Muse, William (1831 Jan 26)
Mustoe, Anthony (1793 Jun 27)
Mustoe & Chambers (1789 Oct 6; 1790 Jun 25)
Myers, Peter (1824 Sep 1)
Naylor, Robert F. (1832 Sep 25)
Nelson, Alexander (1792 Mar 9)
Nelson, James (1836 Apr 12; 1842 Jan 8)
Nelson, William, Jr. (1789 Aug 3, 11)
Nevel, Zachariah (n.d.)
Newell, Thomas (1818 Jan 30; 1819 Jun 21; 1823 Jan 25; 1826 Nov 13)
Nicholas, Philip Norborne (1802 Jan 18, Feb 28, Mar 14, 20; 1803 Jan 18; 1844 May 14)
Nichols, William (1797 Jan 27)
North, Catherine (1776 Sep 10, Oct 24, Dec 10; 1777 Feb 7, all re the death and estate of Matthew Read)
North, John A. (1834 Jul 28, Aug 5, Nov 20; 1835 May 18; 1836 Aug 15; 1837 Mar 20; 1839 Feb 23; ca. 1842 Jan 20)
Nowlin, Bryan W. (1833 May 31, Jul 22)
O'Neal, Joseph (1792 Jan 23)
Otey, H. (1848 Apr 11)
Ott, Henry (1842 Mar 31)
Ott, Jacob, Jr. (1842 Apr 1)
Page, Robert (1832 Mar 2)
Page, William (1842 Sep 30)
Park, Catherine (1778 Dec 29, see also Catherine North)
Parks, Andrew (1831 May 28, 30, June 8; 1832 Sep 23; 1833 Dec 10; 1835 Oct 14, 21)
Patton, Robert (1820 May 22)
Patterson, John (1790 Nov 12)
Patterson, [Lloyd] M. (1816 Dec 10)
Patterson, William (1832 Nov 12)
Paul, Andrew (1797 Mar 19)
Paul, John (n.d.)
Pauly, L. (1834 Mar 22, with enclosures)
Paxton, Jonathan (1840 Sep 22)
Payne, George H. (1838 Nov 1, 18)
Payne, William (ca. 1840)
Peachey, William (1799 Sep 19)
Peck, Jacob C. (1834 Jun 10)
Peck, Joseph (1836 Jun 10)
Pendleton, Henry (1819 Mar 23; 1821 Dec 29)
Pendleton, Philip C. (1836 Feb 28)
Pennington, Wheeler (1818 Jan 27)
Pennybacker, Isaac Samuels (1836 Aug 4; 1846 May 25)
Perley, William Lee (1820 Apr 4)
Peters, Henry (1834 Feb 3, as an enclosure)
Peyton, Bernard (1819 Apr 5; 1823 Feb 15; 1824 Aug 16; 1836 Mar 29)
Peyton, G. (1820 Jun 6)
Peyton, J. (1793 May 9)
Peyton, John Howe (1820 Mar 5; 1832 Sep 21; 1836 May 8; 1843 Nov 15; 1846 Dec 3; 1847 Jan 17)
Peyton, John L[ewis] (1841 Jan 21)
Peyton, John S. (1817 Jun 21 re the sale of Mrs. Briscoe's slaves)
Peyton, V. (1835 Dec 17)
Phillips, David (1834 Oct 28)
Pilson, Matthew (1837 Nov 8)
Pitzer, Madison (1835 Jan 3)
Plumer, William Swan, Rev. (1841 Aug 18)
Plumer & Wilson (1838 Oct 29)
Poor & Keyser (1837 Nov 16; 1841 Jul 15)
Potter, William (1838 Nov 14)
Powell, L.M. (1861 Jan 19)
Pratt & Keith (1839 May 13)
Pressly, William P. (1836 Dec 2)
Preston, Robert (1836 Nov 18)
Priestly, James (1791 Oct 10)
Rader, George (1831 Feb 2, Apr 31; 1834 Sep 5; 1835 Mar 11; 1838 Oct 15)
Rader, John (1836 Mar 7)
Ralston, William (1833 Aug 25; 1834 Jan 29)
Randolph, John (1838 Apr 2)
Ranson, James M. (ca. 1842 Jun 8 asking to marry Briscoe Gerard Baldwin's daughter; 1844 May 21)
Ranson, M.E. (Baldwin), daughter of B.G. Baldwin (ca. 1835 Oct 29 as part of another letter from M.S. Baldwin; 1842 Jan 26)
Reid, A. (1794 Apr 3 re an election)
Reid, Samuel McDowell (1821 Jun 21; 1830 May 27; 1837 Mar 24)
Reimensnyder, John J. (1833 Nov 4)
Reimensnyder, George H., Rev. (1832 Apr 21; 1833 Jun 23)
Reynolds, John (1822 Oct 16)
Reynolds, Johnson (1833 May 18)
Richards, Barbara (1832 Oct 14)
Richardson, J. (1836 Mar 30)
Richardson, Robert (1791 Jun 20)
Richardson, William Harvie (1834 Aug 8 re regimental news)
Rind, James (1790 Nov 10)
Risque, James (1807 Jan 29; Dec 8)
Robertson, Joseph H. (1840 Sep 11 re the Harrison County Democratic Convention )
Robinett, Jesse ([1778 Nov])
Rogers, James B. (1831 Sep 19; 1834 Oct 15, Nov)
Ronald, Andrew (1792 Mar 27)
Rose, Charles (n.d.)
Rose, Robert S. (1803 Mar 23)
Ross, A.H. (1841 Jan 19)
Ross, John (1795 Mar 3; 1796 Feb 27; 1800 Mar 20)
Rowe, Benjamin (1791 Apr 15)
Rowland, William (1833 Apr 20)
Ruff, John (1833 Nov 19; 1834 Jun 6, 7, Nov 15; 1838 Apr 25; 1839 May 23, Nov 12)
Ruffner, Henry (1830 Mar 24 re the election of a president for Washington College)
Rupert, James C. (1839 Feb 8)
Russle, James (1836 Oct 24)
Rust, James (1834 Nov 25; 1837 Jan 28; 1838 May 22; 1839 Mar 13, Apr 16)
Ryle, David (1798 Jan 24)
Samuel, G.B. (1841 Dec 8)
Samuels, Joseph H. (1840 Feb 7; 1846 Oct 12)
Sanders, Lewis (1836 Feb 17, Apr 13 re his confinement in jail, Sep 10)
Sanders, R.W. (1846 May 13)
Sangston, Robert (1834 Feb 23)
Schnebly, Daniel (1828 Jun 20; 1832 May 8, as enclosure)
Schroeder, (Henry) & Son (1814 Mar 12)
Scott, Christopher C. (1831 Jul 13)
Scott, Nancy (1834 Nov 30)
Settle, Wilford G. (1835 Apr 18, 28, Sep 28; 1836 Sep 28; 1838 Sep 27; 1840 Apr 26)
Sevier, G.W. (1827 May 6)
Shanks, James (1836 July 19)
Shaw, Matthew (1835 Aug 25)
Sheffey, Hugh W. (1842 Feb 7 re congratulations on Baldwin becoming Judge of the Court of Appeals)
Sheffey, James W. (1835 Jun 12, Nov 23; 1836 Mar 18, Oct 26; 1837 Mar 10, Nov 27; 1839 Aug 12)
Sheffey, Mrs. Mary (1835 July 24 re the sale of a slave; 1836 Oct 9, Oct, Nov 8, Dec 22)
Shelton, Joseph S. (1841 Feb 19)
Sherman, Edmund (1820 July 1)
Shiflet, Absalom (1835 Aug 24)
Shipman, J. (n.d.)
Shue, Jacob (1835 Jun 9)
Shumate, William (1839 Jan 2)
Sheetz, Henry (1834 Oct 4)
Skillern, George (1790 Oct 7)
Skouton, Solomon (1834 Mar 22; 1838 Nov 27; 1839 Feb 13, Apr 2; 1840 Feb 10, Jun 24, Sep 15; 1841 Mar 27)
Slater, Joseph (1797 Jul [4]; 1798 Mar 20, May 23; n.d.)
Smith, A.C., Col. (1835 Apr 30)
Smith, Abraham (1837 May 25)
Smith, E.H. (1834 Apr 12 re the 116th regiment)
Smith, Francis H., Superintendent of Virginia Military Institute, 1812-1890, (1845 May 21, Oct 1; 1846 Jul 8, Oct 1; 1847 Jan 11, Mar 25, Apr 1)
Smith, John M. (1836 Mar 14; 1837 Jun 8; 1838 Jun 18)
Smith, P. Frazer (1860 Feb 21)
Smith, William (1833 Dec 7)
Smyth, James B. (1821 May 15; 1823 May 24)
Snyder, Mathias (1821 May 15)
Southern, Robert H. (1831 Jun 11)
Sowers, John C. (1841 Jan 13)
Spangler, C.H. (1818 Nov 26)
Spangler, Joseph (1817 Mar 29)
Spangler, Levy (1821 Jan 23)
Speck, H. (1834 Jul 30)
Spiece, John B. (1831 May 17; 1837 Nov 18; 1838 Mar 16, Dec 1; 1839 Jan 26; 1840 Apr 12)
Spotts, James C. (1832 Dec 21)
Stanard, Robert (1820 Jul 6; 1838 Mar 4)
Stanton, Robert C. (1835 Feb 22)
Steel, John, Capt. (1783 Oct 13)
Steel, M. (1836 Apr 24)
Steele, John (1831 Aug 20; 1833 Sep 2; 1834 Jun 11)
Steele, Robert (1829 Feb 17; 1830 Mar 1; 1833 Jun 8; 1834 Jun 6)
Steeth, David W. Jr. (1838 Aug 8)
Sterrett, Thomas (1818 Jun 22)
Sterrett, William H. (1839 Jan 26, Feb 24)
Stevens, Edward (1837 Mar 16)
Stevens, S.S. (1815 Dec 17)
Stewart, E.G. (1786 Oct 6)
Stickley, Daniel (1833 Mar 9; 1835 Jul 14 re the misconduct of an officer)
Strange, William F. (1838 Oct 8, Nov 10)
Stribling, Erasmus (1815 Apr 8; 1816 Aug 27)
Stribling, George W. (1834 Jun 2; 1838 Jan 13)
Stringer, David (1833 Oct 28)
Strode, C.E.B. (1831 Jul 12)
Stuart, Alexander (1771 Oct - 1772 Feb; 1794 Nov 29; 1796 Dec 12 to Mr. Rose, Dec 12 to Gavin Lawson; 1802 Jan 30; 1803 Oct 26; 1812 Mar 16; 18[13] Sep 30; 1815 May 26 re plot and survey of Dunsplace; n.d.)
Stuart, Alexander Hugh Holmes, 1807-1891, (1834 Oct 15; 1835 May 13; 1837 Feb 19, Mar 8, Sep 4; 1838 Jul 26; 1839 Mar 14, Aug 4; 1842 Jan 13, Feb 4 re congratulations on Baldwin becoming Judge of the Court of Appeals and abolition; Dec 31; 1844 Jan 21, Feb 6 announcing the birth of a daughter, Sep 9, Nov 13 re electing Polk president and the Whigs; 1845 Jan 2, Feb 15 re epidemics, Jul 16, Aug 23, Sep 3; 1846 Nov 2; possibly 1856 Aug 18 and Sep 29)
Stuart, Archibald, 1795-1855, (1800 Aug 8; 1801 Feb 18; 1802 Oct 26; 1808 Sep 6; 1812 Jun 21; 1816 Sep 19; 1822 Mar 29; 1839 Feb 10)
Stuart, Archibald P. (1833 Oct 2; 1838 Nov 29; 1839 Jan 7, Sep; 1840 Mar 24)
Stuart, Briscoe Baldwin (1844 Jan 30)
Stuart, Frances Cornelis (Baldwin) (1844 Sep 1, Oct 15; 1845 Sep 12)
Stuart, Gerard B. (1820 Mar 8)
Stuart, James (1791 Dec 1)
Stuart, Lewis (1831 Aug 5)
Stuart, M.J. (1845 Jan 17)
Stuart, Maggie B. (1773 Sep 3; 1819 Jul 4)
Stuart, Thomas Jefferson (1843 Jul 25)
Summers, George William, 1804-1868, (1838 Jan 11, Dec 28)
Sutherland, Joseph (1836 Oct 19)
Swann, Margaret (1838 Dec 20)
Swely, Harrison D. (1839 Jun 4)
Swindler, Andrew (1836 Jan 16)
Swindler, Drake (1831 Jun 13; 1833 Aug 23, Dec 30; 1834 Mar 10, Jul 5; 1835 Feb 9; 1836 Oct 17)
Switzer, Newton (1832 Mar 7; 1833 Jun 10)
Swoope, Jacob (1824 Jan 10; 1831 Feb 3)
Swoope, Washington (1837 Mar 7)
Taliaferro, N.M. (1833 Dec 17)
Tate, J.A. (1838 Apr 2)
Taylor, Allen (1825 Apr 16; 1831 Apr 25; 1831 Jun 23; 1833 Sep 16)
Taylor, J.M. (1838 Feb 1)
Taylor, John, 1753-1824, (1786 Mar 1)
Taylor, (Joseph) & Son (1839 Feb 22; 1841 Jul 8)
Taylor, Thomas P. (1846 Mar 5)
Taylor, William (1826 Dec 15; 1834 Jan 13; 1838 Dec 28; 1840 Sep 26)
Taylor, William C. (1834 Feb 19)
Temple, John (1824 Nov 2)
Tennis, B.E. (1834 Mar 16)
Terrill, Robert (1837 Oct 1; 1838 Feb 27)
Terrill, William H. (1837 Feb 16; 1838 Jan 4; 1839 Apr 15)
Thompson, Philip Rootes (1832 Apr 24; 1837 Mar 13, Apr 1)
Thompson, William B. (1848 Nov 22)
Thomson, John (1837 Oct 10)
Thomson, Matthew (1836 Mar 29)
Thrasher, John (1834 Jun 2)
Tippett, Charles B. (1833 Dec 12; 1834 Sep 20; 1841 Mar 22)
Tisdale, Robert (1826 Dec 8)
Todd, C.S. (1839 Oct 9)
Todd, Samuel (1786 Oct 9; 1790 Aug 23)
Toler, Richard H. (1840 Aug 25 re a Whig Convention)
Travers, John (1841 Oct 15)
Trice, A. (1822 Mar 15)
Trimble, James B. (1837 Dec 23)
Trump, John (1769 Aug 10)
Tucker, B. (1836 Mar 22)
Tucker, George, 1775-1861, (1834 Jun 12)
Tucker, Henry St. George, 1780-1848, (1831 May 5, Jun 5)
Tuley, Joseph (1831 Jul 2; 1833 Aug 20, Oct 1; 1841 Sep 14, Dec 8; 1842 Mar 20)
Tunstall, T.M. (1845 Jun 29)
Tunstall, Warrick (1845 Jul 8; 1849 Nov 25)
Turke, Thomas (1790 Apr 19)
Turner, Robert (1834 Mar 17)
Tyler, Staples & Co. (1838 Aug 13)
Vance (John & Thomas) (1819 Oct 30)
Vanmeter, Joseph (1840 Jun 11)
Vanstavern, N. (1820 Apr 2; 1821 Jul 14)
Vaughn, John (1840 Nov 11)
Vincent, T. (1833 Oct 21)
Waite, Obed, President of the Bank of the Valley (1839 Aug 27, Oct 3, 14)
Walker, E. (1835 Jun 6, Jul 20)
Walker, Thomas (1802 Jan 14; 1816 Aug 27; 1819 Jun 9)
Wallace, William Brown (1833 May 5; 1839 Sep 15)
Walton, George (1836 Nov 10)
Watthall, A.B. (1839 Jun 27)
Watthall, B.W. (1837 Nov 9; 1838 Jan 5)
Watts, Edward (1839 Feb 11)
Watts, James B (1837 May 27)
Watts, John B. (1837 Jan 6; 1841 Jul 2, Nov 20; 1842 Jan 17, Jan 20, Jul 12)
Wayland, Lewis (1832 Feb 22; 1837 Jan 4)
Wayles, John (1772 Oct 8)
Wayt, John (1819 May 8, Jul 30; 1820 May 13)
Weaver, William (1816 Sep 19 (enclosed with 1835 Nov 10); 1824 Jun 5)
Weddle, Andrew (1834 Sep 24)
Welch, Benjamin (1836 Jan 27, Apr 5, Sep 3; 1841 Jun 1)
West, Johnston & Co. (1884 Jun 6)
Wethered, Lewin (1835 Sep 17)
Wethered, P.B. (1839 Jun 6)
Whisler, Margaret (1835 May 23, Jun 3)
Whistler, Henry H. (1837 Feb 8)
White, James [J.] (1836 Aug 24; 1837 Nov 9)
White, John B. (1840 Feb 10)
White, Matthew (1834 Apr 11)
White, Robert (1824 Mar 12; 1838 Feb 16)
Whiting, George C. (n.y. Jul 10)
Whitmore, Daniel (regarding establishing a road, 1836 Apr 21)
Wickham, John (1796 Sep 4)
Williams, John (1834 Jul 4)
Williams, Phillip, Jr. (1825 Sep 29; 1826 Feb 28; 1828 Jan 18; 1832 Sep 26; 1836 Sep 10; 1840 Feb 26, Sep 30)
Williams, William Clayton, 1768-1817, (1789 Oct; n.d.)
Wills, Thomas (1818 Oct 14 re sale of a slave)
Willson, William (1825 Apr; 1837 Jun 7, 23)
Wilson, David J. (1835 Aug 10; 1837 Jan 17; 1838 Mar 12; 1839 Oct 4, Dec 16)
Wilson, James (1772 Oct 17; 1837 Jun 11)
Wilson, John S. (1839 Nov 16)
Wilson, Thomas, 1765-1826, (1784 Feb 28; 1785 Jan 24; 1792 Oct 26)
Windle, William (1838 Jun 22)
Wise, Jacob (1833 May 27)
Wiseman, Samuel (1833 Nov 27)
Woltz, F. (1837 Jun 2)
Wood, James S. (1834 Aug 24; 1839 Sep 13; 1841 Apr 8, 29)
Wood, John F. (1836 Jan 17; 1839 Aug 5)
Wood, Joseph (1821 Jul 14)
Woodville, James L. (1828 Mar 5; 1833 Nov 13; 1834 Apr 28, Jun 4, Nov 14; 1835 Nov 13; 1840 Dec 26; 1841 Mar 4, 13; 1844 Feb 26)
Woodley, Willis H., form letter from the University of Virginia Proctor, (1836 Oct 6)
Woods, James (1831 Jan 10)
Wright, Berry (1819 Oct 18)
Wright, [J.] (1820 Nov 19)
Contents List
- I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence 1769-1816, 14 folders (Box 1)
  - Correspondence 1817-1826, 10 folders (Box 2)
  - Correspondence 1827-1833 Jul, 10 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence 1833 Aug-1835 Apr, 9 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence 1835 May-1836, 10 folders (Box 5)
  - Correspondence 1837-1839 Mar, 8 folders (Box 6)
  - Correspondence 1839 Apr-1842 Mar, 8 folders (Box 7)
  - Correspondence 1842 Apr-1874, n.d., 8 folders (Box 8)
- II: Legal and Financial Papers, including Miscellaneous Papers
  - Legal and Financial Papers 1742-1815, 11 folders (Box 9)
  - Legal and Financial Papers 1816-1837, 13 folders (Box 10)
  - Legal and Financial Papers 1838-1849, 1856, n.d., 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Account Book [1787 Oct] (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Account of Richard Matthews 1781 (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Judge John Brown 1787-1822, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Alexander Campbell, Estate of ca. 1832 (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Case Summary sent to Alexander H.H. Stuart by Colonel Harvey Gray 1840 Aug 28 (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Court Docket, Botetourt County, Virginia 1824 Apr (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Court Docket, Rockbridge County, Virginia 1821-1825 (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Court Docket, Rockbridge County, Virginia 1832-1841, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Daybook 1790-1793 (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Daybook for Rockingham County, Virginia Court 1788-1796 (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Daybook for Rockbridge County, Virginia Court 1788-1802 (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Thomas Greenwood 1783-1803 (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Guardianship of Joseph Spangler, Emily Spangler and Philip Spangler by George W. Harrison ca. 1811-1832, 1 of 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Guardianship of Joseph Spangler, Emily Spangler and Philip Spangler by George W. Harrison ca. 1811-1832, 1 of 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Indentures, Power of Attorney, Accounts of the Estates of John Harrison and Colonel William Bowyer, and 2 Land Plats involving sawmill site belonging to A. Hunter 1773-1817 (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Lawsuits 1769-1824, 10 folders (Box 12)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Lawsuits 1825-1849, 6 folders (Box 13)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Lawsuits - Coalter's Executors vs Bryan n.d. (Box 13)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Lawsuits - Wood's Heirs vs [Minzie's Appellees?] n.d. (Box 13)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Lawsuits - Notes and Memoranda n.d., 8 folders (Box 14)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Lawsuits - Notes and Memoranda - B.G. Baldwin n.d., 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Lawsuits - Notes of Authorities n.d. (Box 15)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Ledger Book, with index of Archibald Stuart 1817-1819 (Box 15)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Legal Forms and Declaration Notebook [ca. 1820?] (Box 15)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Benjamin Morris 1805-1814 (Box 15)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Notes and Memoranda n.d., 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Notes re Alleged Murder of a Newborn [ca. 1776-1800] (Box 16)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Notes re the Legal Case of James [Trevor's] Heirs vs Legatees ca. 1832 (Box 16)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Notes re Legal Precedents for Current Cases of [Archibald Stuart?] n.d., 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Notes re Miscellaneous Cases ca. 1828-1838, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Notes re Miscellaneous Cases in Botetourt County, Virginia ca. 1830-1840 (Box 16)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Notes re Statute of Limitations 1790 Aug (Box 16)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Matthew Read ca. 1764-1775 (Box 16)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Slave Account Book for Partnership of Gavin Lawson and Alexander [Stewart] 1771 Oct 18-1772 Feb 1 (Box 17)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Alexander [Stuart] Complaint 1801 July 9 (Box 17)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Alexander Stuart ca. 1760-1824, n.d., 2 Folders (Box 17)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Archibald Stuart 1787-1834, n.d., 6 Folders (Box 17)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Eleanor Stuart, 1767?-1858, 1832-1857, n.d., 4 Folders (Box 18)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Jane Stuart, Estate of ca. 1827-1831 (Box 18)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - James Telford 1783-1801 (Box 18)
  - Legal and Financial Papers - Wills (Copies): William Bilbro (1807); Philip Dold (1817); Jacob [Foland ?] (1784); Frederick Haines (1780); James Hays, Sr. (1812); Samuel Hennings (1770); John Higgins (1802); Peter Higgins (1808); James Kennerly (1797); Thomas Lang (1808); Robert [Marky?] (1809); William McKinney (1838); Samuel Merritt (1792); Isaac Mynes (1811) ca. 1770-1838 (Box 18)